<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ZDoc on HIST3814o</title>
    <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ZDoc on HIST3814o</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham and Rob Blades licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 04:15:05 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://craftingdh.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Instructions: May 4</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  getting our Github accounts set up and making our first log entries getting Hypothes.is set up getting Zotero installed   learn how to describe what&amp;rsquo;s gone wrong, and to figure out how to fix it   explore our ignorance: what is dighist?  Listen Feed for the podcast here.
  Read   Sharon Leon, 2016.&amp;lsquo;Returning Women to the History of Digital History&amp;rsquo; [bracket]</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Instructions: May 11</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  learn some of the ways historical information is made available digitally, paying attention to disparities of labour, and of tech  Listen Read Something given. That&amp;rsquo;s a nice way of thinking about it. Of course, much of the data that we are &amp;lsquo;given&amp;rsquo; wasn&amp;rsquo;t really given willingly. When we topic model Martha Ballard&amp;rsquo;s diary, did she give this to us? Of course, she couldn&amp;rsquo;t have imagined what we might try to do to it.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Instructions: May 19</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/3/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:42 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/3/instructions/</guid>
        <description>The 18th is the Long Weekend. Take a break from your school work, if you can. Goals for this week 80% of digital work is transforming and cleaning materials so that they can become amenable to digital investigation. Your goals this week are to learn
 the utility of regular expressions for cleaning and organizing an OCR&amp;rsquo;d document ways of further tidying text with Open Refine exploratory visualization with network analysis  Listen Read   James Baker, 2017.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Instructions: May 25</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week Listen Read Do  When/if you run into trouble, take screenshots (google how to do that for your particular machine) and these can be uploaded into your repository as well. Indeed, you should also keep track of any files you create as part of your weekly work in your repo: these are evidence!  With tech work, if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come together in about 30 minutes, it won&amp;rsquo;t come in an hour.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Instructions: June 1</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week Listen Read I asked on twitter, (as you do),
.twitter-tweet { font: 14px/1.45 -apple-system,BlinkMacSystemFont,&#34;Segoe UI&#34;,Roboto,Oxygen-Sans,Ubuntu,Cantarell,&#34;Helvetica Neue&#34;,sans-serif; border-left: 4px solid #2b7bb9; padding-left: 1.5em; color: #555; } .twitter-tweet a { color: #2b7bb9; text-decoration: none; } blockquote.twitter-tweet a:hover, blockquote.twitter-tweet a:focus { text-decoration: underline; }  most compelling works of digital history? go!
&amp;mdash; Shawn Graham (@electricarchaeo) April 13, 2020 Explore some of the suggestions. Or, take a look at this piece by former Carleton U public history MA student, Cristina Woods:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Setting up Anaconda</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/installing-anaconda/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/installing-anaconda/</guid>
        <description>Introduction Cost = $0.
Anaconda is a platform for data science work. By installing Anaconda, you get access to a series of tools for working in both the Python and R programming languages, plus excellent visual interfaces that reduce (some of) the pain of programming.
When we do work in python, we sometimes need to add more lego-pieces to what we&amp;rsquo;re doing, to accomplish specific tasks. Anaconda comes with very nearly - but not all - of the pieces you might need.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Setting up your Github</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/github/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/github/</guid>
        <description>If any of the instructions below are unclear, annotate this page with hypothesis while being logged into our course reading group. If you spot someone asking for help and you can offer advice, respond to the annotation. Introduction Github is a code sharing website often used by digital historians. &amp;lsquo;Git&amp;rsquo; is a program that takes snapshots of the current state of a folder, and stores them in sequence, allowing you to revert your changes to an earlier state.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>REGEX</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/3/regex/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/3/regex/</guid>
        <description>Introduction A regular expression (also called regex) is a powerful tool for finding and manipulating text. At its simplest, a regular expression is just a way of looking through texts to locate patterns. When you search a website for instance (use ctrl+f in most applications to search, by the way), the search box finds exact matches; there&amp;rsquo;s no room for fuzziness. A regular expression on the other hand can help you find every line that begins with a number, or every instance of an email address, or whenever a word is used even if there are slight variations in how it&amp;rsquo;s spelled.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Voyant</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/voyant/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/voyant/</guid>
        <description>voyant</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sound</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/sound/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/sound/</guid>
        <description> audacity sonification  </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Setting up your Hypothesis</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/hypothesis/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/hypothesis/</guid>
        <description>While watching this video, turn on the closed captions.
Create an account at hypothes.is:
Get the Chrome app or the Firefox bookmarklet:
Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re logged in:
Then join our HIST3814o reading group. If you happen to be reading something, and see an existing annotation that interests you, hit the &amp;lsquo;reply&amp;rsquo; button on the annotation to start a conversation! Sometimes, the person to whom you&amp;rsquo;re replying might be a previous year&amp;rsquo;s student, but that&amp;rsquo;s ok; they might enter into conversation with you.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Wget</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/wget/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/wget/</guid>
        <description>The following combines elements of Ian Milligan&amp;rsquo;s tutorial at The Programming Historian, as well as Kellen Kurschinski&amp;rsquo;s.
Introduction Wget is a program for downloading materials from the web. It is extremely powerful: if we do it wrong we can look like an attacker, or worse, download the entire internet! We use this program on the command line. We will cover some of the basics, and then we will create a little program that uses wget to download materials from Library and Archives Canada.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Open Refine</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/3/open-refine/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/3/open-refine/</guid>
        <description>When you look at the correspondence.csv you created, you&amp;rsquo;ll see that some names appear multiple times. You may also have noticed that many of the names suffered from errors in the text scan (OCR or Optical Character Recognition errors), rendering some identical names in the original document as similar, but not the same, in the file. For example the recipient &amp;ldquo;Juan de Dios Cafiedo&amp;rdquo; is occasionally listed as &amp;ldquo;Juan de Dios CaAedo&amp;rdquo;.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>AntConc</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/antconc/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/antconc/</guid>
        <description>abreviations
antconc
/an example of antconc being used on 1990s juvenile literature in ways that would be completely comparable for eg scottish chapbooks database https://datasittersclub.github.io/site/dsc4/
Lang, Anouk. “DSC #4: AntConc Saves the Day.” The Data-Sitters Club. April 10, 2020. https://datasittersclub.github.io/site/dsc4/.
also this https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://github.com/bea-alex/DH-MSc-POStagging-lesson/blob/master/POStagging.html which does it in a notebook, and uses national library of scotland stuff</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Instructions: June 8</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/6/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/6/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  experience something of the cycle of digital history by trying some exploratory analysis with the tools/approaches you&amp;rsquo;ve learned  Listen Read  Nothing formal from me to read this week.  Do Remember back in week one, how I had you explore that twitter thread by Amalia Skarlatou Levi? This week, you&amp;rsquo;ll be selecting one of those resources she shared (or, if none strike your fancy, something from the resources gathered here) to do some exploratory digital history.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mapping</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/mapping/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/mapping/</guid>
        <description> storymap leaflet webmapping != GIS, pointers to QGIS  </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>APIs</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/apis/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/apis/</guid>
        <description>Sometimes, a website will have what is called an Application Programming Interface or API. In essence, this lets a program on your computer talk to the computer serving the website you&amp;rsquo;re interested in, such that the website gives you the data that you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.
An API is just a way of opening up a program so that another program can interact with it. That is, instead of an interface meant for a human to interact with the machine, there’s an API to allow some other machine to interact with this one.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Setting up your Zotero</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/zotero/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/zotero/</guid>
        <description>Zotero is a piece of software for managing your research. When it is installed, it can extract metadata from websites or pdfs (when these have metadata) and store the information in your very own library. Zotero can be connected to Word or Google Docs so that when it is time to insert a reference, you can select the reference from your library - and then get the machine to automatically format/update your bibliography against whatever citation style you use.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Networks</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/3/networks/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/3/networks/</guid>
        <description>Recall that the index of the collected letters of the Republic of Texas was just a list of letters from so-and-so to so-and-so. We haven&amp;rsquo;t looked at the content of those letters, but the shape of network — the meta data of that correspondence — can be revealing (remember Paul Revere!) When we stitch that together into a network of people connected because they exchanged letters, we end up with a shard of their social network.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Topic Models</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/topic-models/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/topic-models/</guid>
        <description>use the new stuff? throw some tf-idf in here</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Infographics</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/infographics/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/infographics/</guid>
        <description>academic posters infographics  colour theory, layout, stuff from macroscope re scott chapter</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting started with Discord</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/discord/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/discord/</guid>
        <description>What is Discord? You can download Discord here or you can use it in a broswer.
You will receive an invitation email in your Carleton account. It expires after one day, so do join once you get it. It will ask to verify your email; check your spam folder.
Once you&amp;rsquo;re in, there&amp;rsquo;s a welcome message with a reaction emoji at the end - click on the thumbs up to confirm that you&amp;rsquo;ve read the message.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>OCR</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/ocr/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/ocr/</guid>
        <description>Object Character Recognition is a technique that looks at the pattern of light and dark pixels in an image and matches them against the alphabet. The technique was developed against clean type-written pages where the letters were crisply made. On historical documents, things can get pretty hit-and-miss. When we searched the Chronicling America website, we were actually searching the OCR&amp;rsquo;d text that was embedded in each of those pdfs (if you can select text in a pdf, it has a hidden text layer on top of the image.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>This week&#39;s bonus</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/3/bonus/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/3/bonus/</guid>
        <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in other network tools or data cleaning tools, drop me a line. Many folks use R and R Studio and its various network analysis packages, which have the edge over Gephi in that we can write the script and share that, rather than long, tortured step-by-step &amp;lsquo;click this&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;click that&amp;rsquo; type instructions.
Ah, what the hang, here we go.
Grab this data:
List of links (this downloads a CSV file)</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>This Week&#39;s Bonus</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/bonus/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/bonus/</guid>
        <description>Publish data with datasette to heroku</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Static Websites</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/static-websites/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/static-websites/</guid>
        <description> static website with gh-pages static website with jekyll-now static website with expose link back to academic-kickstarter thing  </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>1. Course Description</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/1-coursedescription/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/1-coursedescription/</guid>
        <description>HIST3814O|DIGH3814O Summer 2020 Department of History, Carleton University This is a methods course about learning to use the huge variety of digitized historical resources available in the world, including some perhaps unconventional sources such as social media. You will learn some of the habits of doing born-digital work, including the doing of digital history as an outward facing public history.
You do not need to be &amp;lsquo;techy&amp;rsquo; to be successful in this course!</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2. Learning Outcomes</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</guid>
        <description>Outcomes  This course will enable you to analyze and assess historical documents, artifacts, and other primary sources through the lens of digital history methods, critically applied, and you will develop awareness of the ways digital tools change what it is possible to know about the past. At the same time, this ability will enable you to analyze and assess critically digital tools and methods from a historical perspective. Given that this is an online course, another outcome will be your ability to conduct such research independently.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3. Course Calendar</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/3-schedule/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/3-schedule/</guid>
        <description>Each week involves completing to the best of your ability a series of exercises; you will document your progress in a weekly log that you will keep online. Log entries are required to be completed by the Sunday evening at the end of the relevant work. A final reflection piece is due at the end of the course. See the assessment page for further details
Week 1, May 4 An overview of digital history</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4. Assessment</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/4-assessment/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:59 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/4-assessment/</guid>
        <description>There is no midterm. There is no final exam. Weekly Exercises Each week, there are set exercises for you to attempt.
Weekly work should be completed by the end of the relevant week.
I am not looking for &amp;lsquo;correct&amp;rsquo; completion, or that you powered through x amount of them. I am, rather, looking for your evidence of thinking through the meaning of the process: what worked, what didn&amp;rsquo;t, why, and what that might mean for you as a historian.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5. Common Regulations</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/5-commonregs/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/5-commonregs/</guid>
        <description>The following are the University regulations common to all History courses. COPIES OF WRITTEN WORK SUBMITTED Always retain for yourself a copy of all essays, term papers, written assignments or take-home tests submitted in your courses.
PLAGIARISM The University Senate defines plagiarism as “presenting, whether intentionally or not, the ideas, expression of ideas or work of others as one’s own.” This can include:
 reproducing or paraphrasing portions of someone else’s published or unpublished material, regardless of the source, and presenting these as one’s own without proper citation or reference to the original source; submitting a take home examination, essay, laboratory report or other assignment written, in whole or in part, by someone else; using ideas or direct, verbatim quotations, or paraphrased material, concepts, or ideas without appropriate acknowledgment in any academic assignment; using another’s data or research findings; failing to acknowledge sources through the use of proper citations when using another’s works and/or failing to use quotation marks; handing in &amp;ldquo;substantially the same piece of work for academic credit more than once without prior written permission of the course instructor in which the submission occurs.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6. Contacting Dr. Graham</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/6-contact/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/6-contact/</guid>
        <description>Dr. Graham can be found online at
shawn dot graham at carleton dot ca
or on Twitter at @electricarchae.
He will be present in our Crafting Digital History discord server every day.
If we ever get out of quarantine, and you&amp;rsquo;re in Ottawa, he often haunts the Library coffeeshop.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7. Colophon</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/7-colophon/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/docs/7-colophon/</guid>
        <description>This course originally was a face-to-face class, over 13 weeks. That let us get into the nitty-gritty of different approaches and platforms; it gave us the opportunity to have guest speakers; and most importantly, it gave us the time to really grapple with different kinds of historical &amp;lsquo;capta&amp;rsquo; (see Drucker on &amp;lsquo;capta versus data&amp;rsquo;). But, needs evolved and eventually the course moved fully online. Now only 6 weeks long, a lot of things have been cut, compressed, or rethought entirely.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Asking for help</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/help/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/help/</guid>
        <description>Help! Things have gone wrong! Montparnasse Derailment, 1895
Things are going to go wrong. Things are going to break. Instructions will seem vague or incomplete - or worse, I will have indeed forgotten to tell you something crucial.
Or worse, I&amp;rsquo;ve made an assumption about your understanding, and left things unsaid that needed to be made explicit. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of this, in the digital world, in fact.
This week, you learned a bit about Git and Github.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>This week&#39;s bonus</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/bonus/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/2/bonus/</guid>
        <description>Historian&amp;rsquo;s don&amp;rsquo;t deal with video very well. That is to say, we don&amp;rsquo;t have many tools for dealing with video as video, as a moving image, and analyzing with an eye towards the specific affordances of the medium (but see Arnold and Tilton&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Distant Viewing&amp;rsquo; project, and their position paper.)
But we&amp;rsquo;re good with text. In this bonus exercise, you&amp;rsquo;ll download a video from youtube of Dr. Martin Luther King&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;I have a dream&amp;rsquo; speech (wikipedia), and use Google&amp;rsquo;s speech-to-text engine to generate a time-stamped transcript of the speech.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Final Submission Instructions</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/6-5/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/6-5/instructions/</guid>
        <description>The Last Bit Do Reflect Submit work You can submit the link to your work on this form</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>This Week&#39;s Bonus</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/bonus/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/bonus/</guid>
        <description> exhibit with Wax Omeka - reclaimhosting, links to tutorials Neatline - links to tutorials  </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Placeholder Text</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/blog/placeholder/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/blog/placeholder/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Click title to see the full Post&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorem est tota propiore conpellat pectoribus de&lt;br /&gt;
pectora summo. Redit teque digerit hominumque toris verebor lumina non cervice&lt;br /&gt;
subde tollit usus habet Arctonque, furores quas nec ferunt. Quoque montibus nunc&lt;br /&gt;
caluere tempus&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>