<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Week 5: June 1 on HIST3814o</title>
    <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Week 5: June 1 on HIST3814o</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham and Rob Blades licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Instructions: June 1</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Telling the Compelling Story Eventually, after many cycles of cleaning data, making exploratory visualizations, and rerunning your analyzes, you will arrive at a point where you have this thing that you want to communicate. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s part of a larger story, and illuminates some aspect that was hitherto hidden. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s the entire story. Perhaps it only sets up the questions for a deeper investigation. There will come a moment when you want to communicate and tell this compelling story.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sound</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/sound/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/sound/</guid>
        <description>Podcasting As you may be thinking to yourself, &amp;lsquo;how can he teach us anything about podcasting, he&amp;rsquo;s not terribly good at it&amp;rsquo;.
Fair enough. I first encountered podcasting back in about 2005 - ipod, hence podcasting - as part of my previous life in the edtech world. It was difficult to do, and most &amp;lsquo;shows&amp;rsquo; weren&amp;rsquo;t terribly good. I never really got into it, as a producer. But in recent years, professional broadcasters have entered the scene, raising production values across the board.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mapping</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/mapping/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/mapping/</guid>
        <description>Telling Stories with StoryMaps The historical stories we want to tell take place within and across space. The Storymapjs platform from the Knight Lab at Northwestern University was developed to make this easier to accomplish. Below is an example the Knight Lab put together concerning Arya Stark&amp;rsquo;s journeys. Note how each point in the map can be annotated with videos, images, or other kinds of rich content. Each point on the map is annotated with text and media; the &amp;lsquo;next arrow&amp;rsquo; moves us to the next point, implying a historical or temporal connection.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Posters</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/posters/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/posters/</guid>
        <description>&amp;lsquo;Accidental Renaissance: the photos that look like Italian paintings&amp;rsquo;.
Here we&amp;rsquo;re going to explore some of the principles of design that are useful for you in the design of academic posters. These same principles are useful for the design of infographics. If an academic poster is the distillation of the same ideas that might turn up in an academic poster, then an infographic is a distillation of an academic poster.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Static Websites</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/static-websites/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/5/static-websites/</guid>
        <description>Building a website from scratch can be onerous. Using a system like Wordpress or Squarespace etc can leave you locked in to someone else&amp;rsquo;s platform (and any security issues that might entail).
Here, we&amp;rsquo;re going to build a simple website that uses nothing but text files as its source; these text files will always be readable into the future, and you can also copy them to your own machine so that they&amp;rsquo;re always handy, ready to be transformed into something else.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>