<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Week 1: May 4 on HIST3814o</title>
    <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Week 1: May 4 on HIST3814o</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham and Rob Blades licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Instructions: May 4</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  getting our Github accounts set up and making our first log entries getting Hypothes.is set up getting Zotero installed   learn how to describe what&amp;rsquo;s gone wrong, and to figure out how to fix it   explore our ignorance: what is dighist?  Listen Feed for the podcast here.
  Read   Sharon Leon, 2016.&amp;lsquo;Returning Women to the History of Digital History&amp;rsquo; [bracket]</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Setting up your Github</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/github/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/github/</guid>
        <description>If any of the instructions below are unclear, annotate this page with hypothesis while being logged into our course reading group. If you spot someone asking for help and you can offer advice, respond to the annotation. Introduction Github is a code sharing website often used by digital historians. &amp;lsquo;Git&amp;rsquo; is a program that takes snapshots of the current state of a folder, and stores them in sequence, allowing you to revert your changes to an earlier state.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Setting up your Hypothesis</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/hypothesis/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/hypothesis/</guid>
        <description>While watching this video, turn on the closed captions.
Create an account at hypothes.is:
Get the Chrome app or the Firefox bookmarklet:
Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re logged in:
Then join our HIST3814o reading group. If you happen to be reading something, and see an existing annotation that interests you, hit the &amp;lsquo;reply&amp;rsquo; button on the annotation to start a conversation! Sometimes, the person to whom you&amp;rsquo;re replying might be a previous year&amp;rsquo;s student, but that&amp;rsquo;s ok; they might enter into conversation with you.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Setting up your Zotero</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/zotero/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/zotero/</guid>
        <description>Zotero is a piece of software for managing your research. When it is installed, it can extract metadata from websites or pdfs (when these have metadata) and store the information in your very own library. Zotero can be connected to Word or Google Docs so that when it is time to insert a reference, you can select the reference from your library - and then get the machine to automatically format/update your bibliography against whatever citation style you use.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting started with Discord</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/discord/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/discord/</guid>
        <description>What is Discord? You can download Discord here or you can use it in a broswer.
You will receive an invitation email in your Carleton account. It expires after one day, so do join once you get it. It will ask to verify your email; check your spam folder.
Once you&amp;rsquo;re in, there&amp;rsquo;s a welcome message with a reaction emoji at the end - click on the thumbs up to confirm that you&amp;rsquo;ve read the message.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Asking for help</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/help/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/1/help/</guid>
        <description>Help! Things have gone wrong! Montparnasse Derailment, 1895
Things are going to go wrong. Things are going to break. Instructions will seem vague or incomplete - or worse, I will have indeed forgotten to tell you something crucial.
Or worse, I&amp;rsquo;ve made an assumption about your understanding, and left things unsaid that needed to be made explicit. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of this, in the digital world, in fact.
This week, you learned a bit about Git and Github.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>