<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorials on HIST3814o</title>
    <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorials on HIST3814o</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham and Rob Blades, with additions by Chantal Brousseau licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:08:29 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Tutorial Progression for New Digital Historians</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/1-basic-progression/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/1-basic-progression/</guid>
        <description>Introduction Everyone comes to digital work with differing levels of prior familiarity with computing. You do not need to be &amp;lsquo;techy&amp;rsquo; (whatever that is), but you do need to be open to learning from things that fail. This can uncomfortable.
For all of the tutorials that you attempt, I require that you keep a log of your work. For this, you create a text file in which you keep your thoughts, the error messages, the solutions you try, the websites you go to for help, the advice you get from others, and so on.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Discord</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/discord/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/discord/</guid>
        <description>What is Discord? You can download Discord here or you can use it in a broswer.
You will receive an invitation email in your Carleton account. It expires after one day, so do join once you get it. It will ask to verify your email; check your spam folder.
Once you&amp;rsquo;re in, there&amp;rsquo;s a welcome message with a reaction emoji at the end - click on the thumbs up to confirm that you&amp;rsquo;ve read the message.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Basics of Markdown</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/markdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/markdown/</guid>
        <description>Have you ever fought with Word or another word processor, trying to get things just right? Word processing is a mess. It conflates writing with typesetting and layout. Sometimes, you just want to get the words out. Other times, you want to make your writing as accessible as possible&amp;hellip; but your intended recipient can&amp;rsquo;t open your file, because they don&amp;rsquo;t use the same word processor. Or perhaps you wrote up some great notes that you&amp;rsquo;d love to have in a slideshow; but you can&amp;rsquo;t, because copying and pasting preserves a whole lot of extra gunk that messes up your materials.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Github</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/github/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/github/</guid>
        <description>If any of the instructions below are unclear, annotate this page with hypothesis while being logged into our course reading group. If you spot someone asking for help and you can offer advice, respond to the annotation. Or ping me with an email or on discord! I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to trap you; I want questions! Introduction Github is a code sharing website often used by digital historians. &amp;lsquo;Git&amp;rsquo; is a program that takes snapshots of the current state of a folder, and stores them in sequence, allowing you to revert your changes to an earlier state.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Anaconda</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/anaconda/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/anaconda/</guid>
        <description>Introduction Cost = $0.
Anaconda is a platform for data science work. By installing Anaconda, you get access to a series of tools for working in both the Python and R programming languages, plus excellent visual interfaces that reduce (some of) the pain of programming.
When we do work in python, we sometimes need to add more lego-pieces to what we&amp;rsquo;re doing, to accomplish specific tasks. Anaconda comes with very nearly - but not all - of the pieces you might need.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cleaning &amp; Manipulating Data with R</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/clean-data-r/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/clean-data-r/</guid>
        <description>Cleaning and Manipulating Data with R We&amp;rsquo;re going to use data from pulled from the The Survey of Scottish Witchcraft Database for this tutorial; this tutorial was written by Chantal Brousseau.
So maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve created a dataset by scraping the web, or found some really cool open data but&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s messy! You try to make visuals with it, but there&amp;rsquo;s so many nonsense characters and repeating words that your data seems meaningless!</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Excel &amp; R</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/excel/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/excel/</guid>
        <description>I might be making a terrible assumption, but I&amp;rsquo;m assuming that many if not most of you have played around with Excel before. What follows is a very basic introduction, just in case. Library and Archives Canada provides links to historical census data, along with quite comprehensive discussion about how the material was digitized, how it was collected in the first place, and the limitations of the data.
Unfortunately, none of it is available as a simple table that we could download.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Wget</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/wget/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/wget/</guid>
        <description>The following combines elements of Ian Milligan&amp;rsquo;s tutorial at The Programming Historian, as well as Kellen Kurschinski&amp;rsquo;s.
Introduction Wget is a program for downloading materials from the web. It is extremely powerful: if we do it wrong we can look like an attacker, or worse, download the entire internet! We use this program on the command line. We will cover some of the basics, and then we will create a little program that uses wget to download materials from Library and Archives Canada.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Git on the Command Line</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/more-github/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/more-github/</guid>
        <description>Simple Versioning with Git &amp;amp; Github Git is a program you can put on your computer to take periodic &amp;lsquo;snapshots&amp;rsquo; or commits of the contents of your folder. Each snapshot gets a descriptive message about why you&amp;rsquo;ve taken that snapshot. Git can also let you create &amp;lsquo;branches&amp;rsquo; for your work from a given point. You might want to do an experiment; a branch is a copy of your folder that you can work on and, if the experiment doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, you may discard that branch and everything goes back to normal.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>APIs</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/apis/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/apis/</guid>
        <description>Sometimes, a website will have what is called an Application Programming Interface or API. In essence, this lets a program on your computer talk to the computer serving the website you&amp;rsquo;re interested in, such that the website gives you the data that you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.
An API is just a way of opening up a program so that another program can interact with it. That is, instead of an interface meant for a human to interact with the machine, there’s an API to allow some other machine to interact with this one.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hypothesis</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/hypothesis/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/hypothesis/</guid>
        <description>While watching this video, turn on the closed captions.
Create an account at hypothes.is:
Get the Chrome app or the Firefox bookmarklet:
Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re logged in:
Then join our HIST3814o reading group. If you happen to be reading something, and see an existing annotation that interests you, hit the &amp;lsquo;reply&amp;rsquo; button on the annotation to start a conversation! Sometimes, the person to whom you&amp;rsquo;re replying might be a previous year&amp;rsquo;s student, but that&amp;rsquo;s ok; they might enter into conversation with you.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Jupyter and Python</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/jupyter/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/jupyter/</guid>
        <description>Introduction A jupyter notebook is a way of working with code (in a variety of programming languages) in discrete cells, alongside text, images, figures, videos, and links (written using markdown). Sometimes this is called &amp;lsquo;literate programming&amp;rsquo; because it allows you to weave your narrative about the work, the transformations you&amp;rsquo;re making, the analysis you&amp;rsquo;re doing, around the code itself. In this way, a reader progressing from start to bottom can both replicate your work and reproduce it in other contexts.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>OCR</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/ocr/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/ocr/</guid>
        <description>Object Character Recognition is a technique that looks at the pattern of light and dark pixels in an image and matches them against the alphabet. The technique was developed against clean type-written pages where the letters were crisply made. On historical documents, things can get pretty hit-and-miss. When we searched the Chronicling America website, we were actually searching the OCR&amp;rsquo;d text that was embedded in each of those pdfs (if you can select text in a pdf, it has a hidden text layer on top of the image.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Point Map with Google Maps</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/google-sheets-maps/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/google-sheets-maps/</guid>
        <description>The Google ecosystem has a wide variety of tools that can be made to work in concert. One thing that can be done is to use a Google sheet as the data source for a Google map. If you have data on your own machine in a spreadsheet file or a csv file, you can upload your data to Google Sheets and then plumb that data through the maps. Boom! A very useful process.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Twine &amp; Interactive Historical (non) Fiction</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/twine/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/twine/</guid>
        <description>Digital history isn&amp;rsquo;t just about computational analysis or mapwork or computer vision or AI (though of course, it can encompass those things.) It can also create compelling stories and experiences. Sometimes, these can involve very complex websites and underlying js code and so on.
But sometimes, it can be achieved much more simply.
Before video games went all-in on powerful graphics, games (and playful engagements) could create deep simulations and immersive worlds simply through text.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Zotero</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/zotero/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/zotero/</guid>
        <description>Zotero is a piece of software for managing your research. When it is installed, it can extract metadata from websites or pdfs (when these have metadata) and store the information in your very own library. Zotero can be connected to Word or Google Docs so that when it is time to insert a reference, you can select the reference from your library - and then get the machine to automatically format/update your bibliography against whatever citation style you use.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Network Analysis in Python</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/networks-python/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/networks-python/</guid>
        <description>This tutorial follows Melanie Walsh&amp;rsquo;s Networks tutorial from her course Introduction to Cultural Analytics with some minor modifications.
Network analysis is all about looking at the patterns of relationships we find in our data, and seeing how individual &amp;lsquo;nodes&amp;rsquo; are positioned vis-a-vis all the other ones, or what the emergent, macroscopic patterns might imply about how the entire population of &amp;hellip;whatever it is you&amp;rsquo;re studying&amp;hellip; might experience things like group identity or flows of information.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Network Analysis in R</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/networks-r/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/networks-r/</guid>
        <description>Network analysis is all about looking at the patterns of relationships we find in our data, and seeing how individual &amp;lsquo;nodes&amp;rsquo; are positioned vis-a-vis all the other ones, or what the emergent, macroscopic patterns might imply about how the entire population of &amp;hellip;whatever it is you&amp;rsquo;re studying&amp;hellip; might experience things like group identity or flows of information. In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;re looking at a network of correspondence between important figures in the Republic of Texas.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Networks with Databasic and Gephi</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/networks/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/networks/</guid>
        <description>Recall that the index of the collected letters of the Republic of Texas was just a list of letters from so-and-so to so-and-so. We haven&amp;rsquo;t looked at the content of those letters, but the shape of network — the meta data of that correspondence — can be revealing (remember Paul Revere!) When we stitch that together into a network of people connected because they exchanged letters, we end up with a shard of their social network.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Open Refine</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/open-refine/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/open-refine/</guid>
        <description>In the regex tutorial we worked with the correspondence of the Republic of Texas, and independent state from 1835 to 1846 was collated into a single volume and published with a helpful index in 1911. It was scanned and OCR&amp;rsquo;d by Google, and is now available as a text file from the Internet Archive. You can see the OCR&amp;rsquo;d text at archive.org.
You can right-click and download a version of the semi-cleaned file from here.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>REGEX</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/regex/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/regex/</guid>
        <description>Introduction A regular expression (also called regex) is a powerful tool for finding and manipulating text. At its simplest, a regular expression is just a way of looking through texts to locate patterns. When you search a website for instance (use ctrl+f in most applications to search, by the way), the search box finds exact matches; there&amp;rsquo;s no room for fuzziness. A regular expression on the other hand can help you find every line that begins with a number, or every instance of an email address, or whenever a word is used even if there are slight variations in how it&amp;rsquo;s spelled.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>AntConc</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/antconc/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/antconc/</guid>
        <description>Follow this tutorial by Heather Froelich to install and use AntConc, but give it a try on this corpus of historical documents I have prepared for you. This corpus comes from the National Library of Scotland collection of chapbooks printed in Scotland. The data is the OCR&amp;rsquo;d text from more than 3000 chapbooks, mostly from the 18th and 19th centuries. A chapbook was a cheaply printed booklet, and dealt with popular subjects.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Simple Image Analysis</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/image/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/image/</guid>
        <description>Image Analysis In recent years, historians have started to deal with photographs or videos / video stills as historical documents. Arnold and Tilton call this &amp;lsquo;distant viewing&amp;rsquo;. There are a variety of ways this might pan out; one might identify and analyze colour and composition of key frames in a recording of a historical event. One might track objects or people. In a recent piece of my own, we asked the computer to identify objects and contexts to describe &amp;lsquo;scenes&amp;rsquo; in images pulled from Instagram, in order to explore how people constructed their own &amp;lsquo;cabinets of curiosities&amp;rsquo; (which you can read here, connected to the trade in human remains.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>TMT Gui</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/tmt/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/tmt/</guid>
        <description>An Introduction to Topic Models   that link at the end of the video, if you&amp;rsquo;re interested: http://bit.ly/sw-tm-tour
Topic Modeling with the TMTool There are many tools that can fit a topic model to your text. The easiest one to use is a graphical user interface overlaid on the MALLET Toolkit called &amp;lsquo;The Topic Modeling Tool&amp;rsquo; by Jonathan Enderle.
 Follow Enderle&amp;rsquo;s instructions for downloading and installing the tool here Make a new directory on your machine called tmt.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Topic Models</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/topic-models/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/topic-models/</guid>
        <description>An Introduction to Topic Models   that link at the end of the video, if you&amp;rsquo;re interested: http://bit.ly/sw-tm-tour
Topic Model in R The Topic Model Tool is an excellent tool for building and exploring topic models. But you might want to try building a topic model in R. R is a powerful language for statistical exploring, visualizing, and manipulating all kinds of data, including textual. While R can be worked with from the command line, RStudio is what we need to preserve our sanity.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Voyant</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/voyant/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/voyant/</guid>
        <description>Text Analysis in a Nutshell   &amp;hellip;so let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at Voyant Tools:
An Introduction to Voyant   &amp;ldquo;The gateway drug to the digital humanities.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s quite a statement - but it&amp;rsquo;s true! What makes Voyant Tools so compelling, in my view, is that it encourages us to play. To take a step back, and turn the knobs and dials and to see what happens next. Voyant encourages us to zoom in and out, looking at the very broad macroscopic and then jump into the micro, and back again.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mapping With Leaflet</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/mapping/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/mapping/</guid>
        <description>Webmapping with Leaflet One of my favourite web maps is by Professor Vincent Brown of Harvard, on the Slave Revolt in Jamaica, 1760 - 1761. He writes, &amp;lsquo;the map suggests an argument about the strategies of the rebels and the tactics of counterinsurgency, about the importance of the landscape to the course of the uprising, and about the difficulty of representing such events cartographically with available sources.&amp;rsquo; Spend a few minutes allowing the map to play (link here) and think about the aesthetic and design choices used to communicate this powerful story.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mapping With Python and Folium</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/folium/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/folium/</guid>
        <description>Geocoding and Mapping in Python There is a complete jupyter notebook you can save to your own machine, and run by first starting Jupyter Notebooks; you&amp;rsquo;ll want this list of Ottawa places.
This notebook file is adapted from Melanie Walsh 2021 &amp;lsquo;Introduction to Cultural Analytics: Mapping&amp;rsquo; https://melaniewalsh.github.io/Intro-Cultural-Analytics/Mapping/Mapping.html. You are encouraged to follow the remainder of her tutorial to learn how to add a custom map background, and how to publish your resulting map to the web.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Posters</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/posters/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/posters/</guid>
        <description>&amp;lsquo;Accidental Renaissance: the photos that look like Italian paintings&amp;rsquo;.
Here we&amp;rsquo;re going to explore some of the principles of design that are useful for you in the design of academic posters. These same principles are useful for the design of infographics. If an academic poster is the distillation of the same ideas that might turn up in an academic poster, then an infographic is a distillation of an academic poster.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sound</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/sound/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/sound/</guid>
        <description>Podcasting As you may be thinking to yourself, &amp;lsquo;how can he teach us anything about podcasting, he&amp;rsquo;s not terribly good at it&amp;rsquo;.
Fair enough. I first encountered podcasting back in about 2005 - ipod, hence podcasting - as part of my previous life in the edtech world. It was difficult to do, and most &amp;lsquo;shows&amp;rsquo; weren&amp;rsquo;t terribly good. I never really got into it, as a producer. But in recent years, professional broadcasters have entered the scene, raising production values across the board.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Static Websites</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/static-websites/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/static-websites/</guid>
        <description>Building a website from scratch can be onerous. Using a system like Wordpress or Squarespace etc can leave you locked in to someone else&amp;rsquo;s platform (and any security issues that might entail).
Here, we&amp;rsquo;re going to build a simple website that uses nothing but text files as its source; these text files will always be readable into the future, and you can also copy them to your own machine so that they&amp;rsquo;re always handy, ready to be transformed into something else.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Storymaps</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/storymaps/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/storymaps/</guid>
        <description>Telling Stories with StoryMaps The historical stories we want to tell take place within and across space. The Storymapjs platform from the Knight Lab at Northwestern University was developed to make this easier to accomplish. Below is an example the Knight Lab put together concerning Arya Stark&amp;rsquo;s journeys. Note how each point in the map can be annotated with videos, images, or other kinds of rich content. Each point on the map is annotated with text and media; the &amp;lsquo;next arrow&amp;rsquo; moves us to the next point, implying a historical or temporal connection.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using the Command Line on Mac OS</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/command-line-mac/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/command-line-mac/</guid>
        <description>Written Walkthrough If you&amp;rsquo;re brand new to this, I strongly recommend you start with watching the video first because it&amp;rsquo;s much more detailed. Of course, if you&amp;rsquo;re confident in your technical abilities or just looking for a refresher, then this written guide to the command line is for you!
Step 1: Accessing the Command Line To navigate the command line in macOS, we use Terminal, which is a built-in application.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using the Command Line on Windows</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/command-line-win/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/tutorials/command-line-win/</guid>
        <description>Written Walkthrough If you&amp;rsquo;re brand new to this, I strongly recommend you start with watching the video first because it&amp;rsquo;s much more detailed. Of course, if you&amp;rsquo;re confident in your technical abilities or just looking for a refresher, then this written guide to the command line is for you!
Step 1: Accessing the Command Line So first thing we&amp;rsquo;re going to want to do is actually open the command line so you can see what it is.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>