<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Week 4: May 25 on HIST3814o</title>
    <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Week 4: May 25 on HIST3814o</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham and Rob Blades licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Instructions: May 25</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Of Macroscopes and Microscopes Goals for this week This week, I want you to begin to have a &amp;lsquo;dialogue with your texts&amp;rsquo;, wherein you learn to use three tools of varying levels of complexity to get distant and close reads on a body of information. Iterating through this cycle, will help you know your data better and see the patterns that would otherwise be lost in all the noise.
When you do this kind of work, it is super important that you make a note of what you expect to find before you do the analysis; as Matthew Lincoln reminds us, we have to do this so that we don&amp;rsquo;t post-facto rationalize what we find as something we already knew&amp;hellip;</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Excel &amp; R</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/excel/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/excel/</guid>
        <description>I might be making a terrible assumption, but I&amp;rsquo;m assuming that many if not most of you have played around with Excel before. What follows is a very basic introduction, just in case. Library and Archives Canada provides links to historical census data, along with quite comprehensive discussion about how the material was digitized, how it was collected in the first place, and the limitations of the data.
Unfortunately, none of it is available as a simple table that we could download.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Voyant</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/voyant/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/voyant/</guid>
        <description>Text Analysis in a Nutshell   &amp;hellip;so let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at Voyant Tools:
An Introduction to Voyant   &amp;ldquo;The gateway drug to the digital humanities.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s quite a statement - but it&amp;rsquo;s true! What makes Voyant Tools so compelling, in my view, is that it encourages us to play. To take a step back, and turn the knobs and dials and to see what happens next. Voyant encourages us to zoom in and out, looking at the very broad macroscopic and then jump into the micro, and back again.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>AntConc</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/antconc/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/antconc/</guid>
        <description>Follow this tutorial by Heather Froelich to install and use AntConc, but give it a try on this corpus of historical documents I have prepared for you. This corpus comes from the National Library of Scotland collection of chapbooks printed in Scotland. The data is the OCR&amp;rsquo;d text from more than 3000 chapbooks, mostly from the 18th and 19th centuries. A chapbook was a cheaply printed booklet, and dealt with popular subjects.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Topic Models</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/topic-models/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/topic-models/</guid>
        <description>An Introduction to Topic Models   that link at the end of the video, if you&amp;rsquo;re interested: http://bit.ly/sw-tm-tour
Topic Modeling with the TMTool There are many tools that can fit a topic model to your text. The easiest one to use is a graphical user interface overlaid on the MALLET Toolkit called &amp;lsquo;The Topic Modeling Tool&amp;rsquo; by Jonathan Enderle.
 Follow Enderle&amp;rsquo;s instructions for downloading and installing the tool here Make a new directory on your machine called tmt.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>This Week&#39;s Bonus</title>
        <link>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/bonus/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://craftingdh.netlify.com/week/4/bonus/</guid>
        <description>Image Analysis In recent years, historians have started to deal with photographs or videos / video stills as historical documents. Arnold and Tilton call this &amp;lsquo;distant viewing&amp;rsquo;. There are a variety of ways this might pan out; one might identify and analyze colour and composition of key frames in a recording of a historical event. One might track objects or people. In a recent piece of my own, we asked the computer to identify objects and contexts to describe &amp;lsquo;scenes&amp;rsquo; in images pulled from Instagram, in order to explore how people constructed their own &amp;lsquo;cabinets of curiosities&amp;rsquo; (which you can read here, connected to the trade in human remains.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>